A Guide to the Steven and Cathi House Architectural Collection, 1992-2002
Digital Library and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Digital Library and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Steven and Cathi House Architectural Collection, 1992-2002
Digital Library and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2006-017
1 box, 6 oversized folders, 0.4 cu. ft
Steven and Cathi House are Virginia Tech alumnae and award winning architects. Their firm House + House is located in San Francisco, California. This collection includes materials about six residential projects located in California and Florida.
Steven and Cathi House
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Steven and Cathi House Architectural Collection was donated to the International Archive of Women in Architecture at the Digital Library and Archives by its creators in 2005. An addition to the collection was donated in 2007.
Biographical Information
Steven and Cathi House are alumnae of the Virginia Tech School of Architecture. In 1982 they opened their own firm, House + House Architects, in San Francisco, California. They have completed a variety of award-winning projects throughout the United States and the Caribbean.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of information about six projects, five in California and one in Florida. The material about each project includes construction documents, and some also have related color photographs of the finished project and written project descriptions. The collection is arranged chronologically by project date. Additional project materials are expected in the future.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by chronologically by project, and divided by type of material. Sets of construction documents are stored in oversized folders.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Separated Material
The following items were transferred to the Special Collections Rare Book room:
House, Steven and Cathi House. Mediterranean Village: an architectural journey. Australia: Images Publishing Group, 2004.
House, Steven and Cathi House. House+House: Choreographing Space: House Design. Australia: Images Publishing Group, 1999.
Contents List
- Langmaid Residence, Oakland, California, 1992-1993
  - Project description (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Photographs of exterior (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Photographs of interior (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Construction plans (20 sheets) (Oversize 1)
- Jarvis Residence, Oakland, California, 1993-1995
  - Project description (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Photographs of exterior (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Photographs of interior (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Construction plans (27 sheets) (Oversize 2)
- De Piazza Paz Residence, Saint Augustine, Florida, 1999
  - Construction plans (27 sheets) (Oversize 3)
- Manzanita Residence, Kings Beach, California, 1999
  - Construction plans (21 sheets) (Oversize 4)
- 14 Harris Place, San Francisco, California, 1999-2000
  - Construction plans (18 sheets) (Oversize 5)
- Howes Tara Residence, Fairfax, California, 2001-2002
  - Construction plans (19 sheets) (Oversize 6)